

# **Zahir Iqbal**

# Marketing | Strategy | Growth

#### **Personal Profile:**

Determined and earnest professional with 4 years of experience in E-Commerce Marketing. Keen on transforming acquired knowledge into actions that optimize revenue for the company. With a strong willingness to learn, prepared to contribute to increased on-site conversion performance and optimize methods for efficiency.

#### **Contact Me:**

Mobile: +971 56 8361237

Address: PO Box 16733 Dubai, UAE

Email: zahir.mohdiqbal@gmail.com

Website: www.zahirux.com

**Linkedin**: www.linkedin.com/in/zahir97/

#### Skills:

- Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Visio)
- JIRA
- Tableau
- PowerBl
- · Google Analytics
- Google Data Studio
- CleverTap
- SOL Advanced
- PowerBl
- Mobile Measurement Partner

#### **Education:**

### **American University of Sharjah**

Major - Finance/ Minor - MIS

January 2017 to December 2019

· Awarded "Exceeds expectation in critical thinking" for "Fundamental of Management"

# Languages:

- English Native or Bilingual Proficiency
- Limited Working Proficiency
- Arabic Elementary Proficiency
- Spanish Elementary Proficiency

#### **Work Experience:**

#### **Marketing Analyst**

**CAFU** 

#### Jan 2023 to Present

- Analyze and inform Marketing Team on transactions and in-app user insights leveraging several analytics platforms such as Firebase, CleverTap, Branch, Google Analytics, and
- Perform A/B test analysis with variants to help the team understand the uplift and impact of campaign performance.
- Create PowerBI Dashboards to help the Marketing Team have visibility over the budget and performance of thirdparty marketing channels such as Meta, Snapchat, Criteo, Google, and Apple Search Ads.

## **Marketing Operations Specialist**

Talabat MENA

Jul 2022 to Jan 2023

- · Mapped over 16 marketing channels' actual budget and MAUs.
- Worked with 8 local marketing teams to analyze the competitive environment in their markets and to educate the regional team about it.
- mapped over 16 marketing channels' budgets and best estimates to Big Query in order to generate an automated Tableau report for 8 markets (MENA).

#### **Growth & Operations Executive**

noon Food

Jun 2020 to July 2022

- · Identified and pursued valuable business opportunities to generate new company revenue and improve bottom-line profitability.
- Developed and executed strategic initiatives to implement key changes and improvements in business development and Marketing programs.
- Customized acquisition tactics based on previous lead data and cross-functional team data, resulting in a +50% increase in onboarding conversion month over month.

#### **Marketing Associate**

Toshiba Elevator & Escalator ME

#### Feb 2018 to Feb 2020

- Developed marketing strategies and resolved problems to drive sales.
- Worked closely with product development teams to create and maintain marketing materials for sales presentations and client meetings.
- Performed ongoing analysis to develop and advance future marketing strategies.